Guide to the Carole Hyatt Papers 1947-2006 (bulk, 1980s-1990s) MS 3105
New-York Historical Society
- Series III. Audiotapes, 1975-2003, undated; 8 Linear feet
  - Subseries III.B. Audiotapes, Not Digitized, 1980-2003, undated; 2 Linear feet in two record cartons (214 tapes)
    The tapes in this subseries are grouped by the original containers they were found in by the processing archvist in 2020. These containers were shoeboxes and other such containers, some with labeling that suggested, at least for some, the overall content. Some tapes were loose in the collection, that is, no longer in a container. Several of the containers were fairly empty and it is possible that tapes were removed from them for digitization. The tapes are boxed in smaller containers labeled A-D within two larger record cartons.
    - Loose tapes, 1980-1994, undated (Box 12, Box 12A)
      32 tapes found together, but loose in the collection. Among these are:
      DATED TAPES: A Conversation with Joyce Hauser: "Women and Work" (1980); Hyatt Job Clinic: "Women and Work" with Joan Hamburg (1980); 2 St. Louis radio interviews (1980); Hyatt/Avon (1983); YMCA Strategic Marketing Workshop (1983); "only child" (1983); Hyatt Associates panel group (1983); "raising daughters; Mothers/daughters" (1984); Shirley and/or Trish Ballard (1985); executive wives seminar (1985); "St. Vincent's" (1987); radio interview (1990); Japan-related (1993-94); Leslie Smith/NAFE/trigger (1994).
      UNDATED: Jean Avery; two unnamed groups; 3 of 4 (one tape missing) re: WSG marketing workshop; "Hyatt"; one unlabeled.
      COMMERCIAL PRODUCTS or OTHER SPEAKERS: 6 sided "Today's Saleswoman" (1982) and tapes by Jack Boland, Zig Zigler, Alan Cimberg, Barbara Tuchman.
    - "Smart People Radio", 1981-1988, undated (Box 12, Box 12B)
      15 tapes found in box labeled "Smart People Radio." These are: "attitude and goal-setting" (1981); 3 radio shows in 1987; 2 radio shows in 1988; Seattle radio show (undated); two undated tapes from WNYC in New York; undated "breakfast with Bob and Betty" with Hyatt and Linda Gottlieb; three tapes from the National Association for Female Executives (NAFE) first national seminar convention, two of which feature Hyatt speaking on "The Selling Game" and "Strategic Marketing Workshop"; a Hyatt presentation tape "How to Sell Yourself and Everything Else"; and one commercial product by Shakti Gawain.
    - "Corporate Survivors", 1990-1991, undated (Box 12, Box 12C)
      18 tapes found in a container labeled "corporate survivors." Holds (1990): Bill Semanie, Maureen Ferguson; (1991): Lee Ann Suriner, Denise Higgins, John Ruehl, Larry Finkelstein, Bob Goddell, Deena Hadley(?), Tom Drucker, and others unidentified; (undated): Cliff Lenz, Dino DeConcini, Jack Pfister, Barbara Davidson, Judith Steinberg, Bob Singerman, and a few others; one unlabeled.
    - "Typed Interview Tapes", 1991, undated (Box 12, Box 12D)
      43 tapes found in container labeled "typed interview tapes." A few are dated 1991; most are undated but seem likely to be from about the same year. Surnames include, among others, Nordstrom, Mazer, Maitlen (1991), Mantyla, McCann, Detroit focus group (1991), Reilly, Roman, Schoenfeld (1991), Freeman, Dallas women focus group, Feld, Strode (1991), San Francisco focus group, Whalen, Tunick, Yavitz (1991), Sedlar, Atlanta focus group (1991), Ashwood, Blanke, Brockner, Horton, Nast, Melanson, Moore Jr., Jones, Perkins, Erkut, Daniel, Francy, Kravitz, Koz, Brown, Cavanaugh, Bride (1991), Aden (1991), Ragovia.
    - "Money Book"/Women's Earnings?, 1995-1997, undated (Box 13, Box 13A)
      19 tapes found in an unlabeled box but that appear to relate to research on the ramifications of women having financial earning power. Surnames include: (1995) McKearnan, Berger, 50+ New York women's group; (1996) Dubrow; (1997) Kahn, Firestone, McCoy, New York/Big Apple women's single group, Iredale, Mancusi, "Bk club gp," Durso, "DC and CH book discussion," "Carole and Deborah"; (undated) Hyde. Also tapes labeled "dictation" (1995) and "Carole" (1997).
    - "Wisdom Tapes", undated (Box 13, Box 13B)
      11 tapes found in box with the label "Wisdom Tapes" in two places, though struckthrough in one of those instances. A set of 8 tapes in the box were banded together; names on those tapes were: Michael Miller, Joe deCola, Doc Severinsen, Focus Group, Bruno Challamel, Eschwan Winding, Terra Mizwa, and one unlabeled. Other tapes in this box were Michael Melia and Men's Architecture Group (2).
    - "Money Book" (Box 13, Box 13B)
      9 tapes found in a container without a label, but small documents, kept with the tapes, indicate these related to Hyatt's research for the "money book." Names include: Dallas focus group (1991), Jean Elliott (1997), "background, money book, Carole and Deborah," (1997), London forum and interviews (3 tapes, 1998), Joanne Mast (1998), and two unlabeled.
    - "Biz Book" Tapes (box 1 of 2), 1988-2003, undated (Box 13, Box 13C)
      Holds 41 of 67 tapes found in a box labeled "Biz Book." Includes surnames: Loren (1999), Lehmann (1999), Jannovitz (1994), Gilligan (1999), D'Agnato, Ward, Bisquat, Goodstein (1994), Montoya (1995), Hubers (1999), Rowell (1999), Kipper (1997), various on tape (2003), University of Illinois (1992), dictation (1994), "When Smart People Fail" (2 copies, 1988) by Carole Hyatt distributed by Church of Today, "The Selling Game" talk by Carole Hyatt distributed by NAFE, "Creating a Buying Atmosphere: Presenting, Probing, Blending" by Carole Hyatt (Transdesign Conf., 3 copies), "Setting Goals: The Playing Piece, Building Affinity and Listening Skills" by Hyatt (NAFE Conf, 3 copies); conference intro (1990), "Shifting Gears" by Hyatt at the International Conference on Outplacement (2 copies), Hyatt on WOR radio (1996), Hair Club for Men, Hamburg (1990), "Shifting Gears" (1991) by Hyatt distributed by Church of Today, Roy (1988, microcassette), and Jack Boland on "The 34th AA Anniversary." Also an envelope of 6 tapes related to "when she earns more" (1997).
    - "Biz Book" Tapes (box 2 of 2), 1983-1999, undated (Box 13, Box 13D)
      Holds 26 of 67 tapes found in a box labeled "Biz Book." Includes "Shifting Gears: Creating Possibilities for Career Change" by Carole Hyatt, presented by Crain's Business Detroit and Strategies (two copies of the packet, each with two tapes, 1992). Includes a set of 5 tapes re: "Shifting Gears", Warwick Hotel (1990). Other names: WLNA radio "Women's Change" (1997), Jim Cracchiolo (1999), Louise Hay, "The Women's Selling Game: Creating a Buying Atmosphere: Presenting, Probing, Blending" by Hyatt (Transdesigns Conference), Pete/WJM (1984), Warsaw discussion (1990), Budapest group, "How to be on Top of the World" by Yyatt (1991), Hair Thinning (1990). Also various commercial products: "Painless Prospecting" by Denise Roberts (2 copies, 1991), Joseph Mancusi "Why Some People and Organizations Will Never Succeed," "Jampolsky/Howe "Healing Relationships" (1984), Jean Houston "Life: The Art of the Possible" (1983), Stephanie Beling "Success with Weight Control" (1989), Jacquelyn Reinach music tape for UN International Year of the Family (1993), and Tim Wheater music tape (1986).
- Series IV. Videotapes, circa 1980-2004, undated; 2 Linear feet
  The series includes 40 videocassette tapes. All but one are VHS format; the exception is a U-Matic, noted in the container list. None of the tapes were viewed during processing so the overall content was only discerned from the labels. Generally, the tapes appear to be recordings of Carole Hyatt's appearances on television talk shows and in other venues, publicity spots and other publicity material, demonstration tapes for workshops, and some presentations.
  All tapes in the series are listed individually below. Quotation marks are used in the container list to indicate wording transcribed from the label(s) on the tape.
  The series is arranged in chronological order, with undated videocassettes at the end.
  - "Good Morning America. The New Man. David Hartman, Carole Hyatt, June Esserman", circa 1980 (Box 10)
  - "Simon & Schuster. Carole Hyatt, Pat Finley", 1984 July (Box 10)
    Second label: "Good Company. July 84"
  - "AT&T. Carole Hyatt. Produced by AT&T. From the 1985 Region Conferences. How to use a 'NO' in Selling" (Box 10)
    Running time: 9:11
  - "Success Strategies/Chevy. 'Life in America.' Danish TV", 1986 April (Box 10)
  - "Uma Silbey. '87 Interviews. NBC, ABC, CNN", 1987 (Box 10)
    Second label: "Today Show (NBC) 2/87 [at] 0:00; Dean Edel Medical Journal (ABC), 5/87 [at] 6:35; Sonya Live in LA (CNN), 8/87, [at] 10:30"
  - "Julie Blacklaw - Seattle", 1987 May (Box 10)
    "Unedited"
  - "Sally Jessie Raphael. Smart People. 1 hour", 1988 March (Box 10)
  - "Carole Hyatt in Tokyo", 1989 July (Box 10)
    Label indicates the tape is Part 2 of 2, but there is no Part 1 in the collection.
  - "Carole Hyatt. Shifting Gears. Kim. 1/2 hour cable TV", 1990 November (Box 10)
  - "Women at Work Seminar. Carole Hyatt. Shifting Gears: The Rocky Road to Success", 1990 November 6 (Box 10)
    Time: 2 hours
  - "Finn Financial Focus. C.H. & Allen Cox", 1990 December 13 (Box 10)
  - "Pat Finley. Seattle Today. Shifting Gears", 1991 January 30 (Box 10)
  - "Carol[e] Hyatt at Home. w/Time Code. Tape #1", 1991 September 16 (Box 10)
  - "Carol[e] Hyatt at Home. w/Time Code. Tape #2", 1991 September 16 (Box 10)
  - "Mrs. Carole Hyatt", 1991 October 3 (Box 10)
    Label is that of Robustelli Video Productions
  - "Carole Hyatt. 'Home' Show. (2nd segment)", 1992 June 25 (Box 10)
  - "Creation of ABC-TV 'Home Show' (10 min), 1992? (Box 10)
  - "CNN. Sonya Live", 1992 December (Box 10)
  - "Carole Hyatt. NAFE Satellite Conference", 1993 May 1 (Box 10)
    National video conference product from NAFE. Hyatt speaks on topic "Reinventing Yourself for Your Next Job or Career". Other speakers on the agenda (but unknown if they are on the tape) are Wendy Reid Crisp, Cokie Roberts, Dr. Linda Hill, and Eleanor Clift.
  - "Women Mean Business. Program Concept. Promo", 1993 (Box 10)
  - "NAFE - Me, Inc. Satellite. Carole Hyatt. 'How to Make Yourself Indispensable'" (2 tapes), 1995 October 21 (Box 10)
    2 tapes, similarly labeled, likely identical
  - "Carole Hyatt: Rainmaker. Womens Selling Game", 1996 April (Box 10)
    With letter from Acadia Pictures (producer of this unedited dub of the Rainmaker workshop)
  - "Money, Style, Power. Carole Hyatt Segment", 1996 December 19 (Box 10)
  - "Keep Your Job!", 1996 (Box 10)
    45 minutes video produced by FORTUNE (magazine) Video
  - "The Peter F. Drucker Award for Nonprofit Innovation", 2000 (Box 10)
    Produced by Peer Education Training Program of SAGE Project, Inc. Time: 21:40.
  - "Strength in Numbers: Women Building Community", 2001 (Box 10)
    Produced by NJN Public Television. Half-hour documentary of highlights of the Fifth Annual Governor's Conference Series on Women's Issues, featuring interviews with various women, including Hyatt.
  - "Afraid of People", 2002 (Box 10)
    Produced by Randall Productions Inc. Time: 56:46.
  - "Carole Hyatt. Mentorship for Success. GIBS Seminar" (2 tapes), 2003 May 2 (Box 10)
    Two tapes labeled the same; one is marked with a "1", the other with a "2." It is not clear if this means there are two copies of the same tape or two parts of a taped program.
  - "Carole Hyatt. 'Getting to Next.' Website Clips", 2003 September 20 (Box 10)
    Three clips: "1) Testimonials, time 1:13; 2) Classroom exchange, time :55; 3) Mentor/Mentee Acknowledgement, time 1:15."
  - "The Image Circle, Inc. Welcomes Carole Hyatt to your Professional Image Enhancement Workshop", 2004 July 7 (Box 10)
  - "Shiting Gears. Demo Tape. Hyatt Associates Inc.", undated (Box 11)
    Time 25:30
  - "Shifting Gears. Student Version. Master", undated (Box 11)
  - "Carole Hyatt. 'Shifting Gears.' Student Version", undated (Box 11)
  - "Carole Hyatt. Demonstration of Keynote & Workshop Presentations", undated (Box 11)
    Handwritten notes on label refer to "How to be Indispensable NAFE Satellite" and "Rainmaking"
  - "In the Prime: Changing Careers with Carole Hyatt", undated (Box 11)
    time: approx. 50 minutes
  - "Carole Hyatt. 'Touches of Hyatt'", undated (Box 11)
    Labeled from Carole Hyatt Associates, Inc, referring to The Woman's Selling Game. Time :19 seconds. Tape format is U-Matic.
  - "FNN -- Carole Hyatt. 'FNN Money Talk'", undated (Box 11)
  - "B. Dalton. 1) 'When Smart People Fail', 2) 'Stop Struggling with Your Teen'", undated (Box 11)
    Time 30 seconds. Appears to be television publicity spots
  - "Modern Maturity" shows, undated (Box 11)
    "Show 7 segment: 'High Sobriety'. Show 9 segment: 'Ellen Terry'. Show 112: Entire length, 28:00"
  - "Bill Filllman. Carol. Tape 1. U. of IL", undated (Box 11)
  - "Cutaways -- RI[?]. Tape 2 SVHS Master", undated (Box 11)
  - "Roundtable final. #3. U. of IL", undated (Box 11)
  - "Tape 1. Copy", undated (Box 11)
    Produced by Modern Communications, Inc.
  - "Cutaways -- Part II w/Post Discussion. Copy. Tape 3", undated (Box 11)
  - [Unknown content. Label is in an Asian language. Tape still shrink-wrapped], undated (Box 11)